

I'm a software engineer with over 6 years of experience across several types of business. Focused on React and it's ecosystem. Experienced in unit testing, React rewriting and refactoring apps and frontend performance. I'm also like to study new techs like Rust and Elixir. In my free time I like to spent time with my dog, family and friends

Employment

Frontend Engineer Canada - Remote

SPOCKET

July 2022 - Present

- · Working as Frontend Engineer with React (using ES6+, React Hooks, Redux, Context API, Jest, RTL and our design system)
- Developing new features iterated from our board using Jira
- · Working and fixing bugs
- Refactoring old components to ES6+ (class components to functional components).
- Configuring the mock service for Jest and RTL
- Improving test coverage
- Implemented a new CI/CD pipeline using Github Actions, AWS S3 and Cloudfront

Software Engineer São Paulo - Remote

DASA April 2021 – July 2022

- · Worked as Frontend Engineer with React (using ES6+, React Hooks, Context API, React Testing Library and Ant Design).
- Developed new features and fixed bugs iterated from our board using Jira.
- Refactored old components to ES6+
- · Created a code standard (only functional components, all typesafe using proptypes and default props)
- Improved the test coverage with the team to 80% (company standards)
- Improved the CI/CD pipeline using Jenkins reducing the problems and time on processing

Full Stack Engineer São Paulo - Remote

SOFTWRAP

August 2020 – April 2021

- Worked with React and React Native, Node.js, Firebase and Docker
- I was responsible to coordinate a specific team for the development of a hybrid application using React Native and Firebase for meal tickets from a disclosed company
- Created a pixel perfect application for accountability of accounting firms

Full Stack Engineer Ribeirão Preto

SMARTENVIOS

February 2020 – June 2020

- · Worked as Full Stack Engineer with React, Gatsby, TailwindCSS, Node.js, PostgreSQL, MongoDB and Docker
- The monitoring process was done using PM2 and the deploying of these services using AWS like LightSail, EC2, S3
- In this position I was responsible for developing, coding and deploying

Education

Universidade de São Paulo

Ribeirão Preto, São Paulo, Brazil

BSc in Biomedical Informatics

2012 - 2020

• During my BSc in biomedical informatics I worked as a intern researcher in bioinformatics where I gained expertise in data analysis using R, more specifically ggplot2, tidyr, dplyr, bioconductor packages(like limma and GEOQuery), and the creation of dashboards using Shiny.



Technology

JAVASCRIPT

- My native programming language. My first contact was in 2013 but started to work a few years after this.
- I've been working with for over 6 years. I've used it in the front-end with React, React Native, Context API, React Hooks, Redux, Zustand consuming
 different backends, using styled-components, Ant Design, TailwindCSS for stylization and for testing automation using React Testing Library and
 Jest
- Using NextJS and Gatsby for personal projects.
- · I've been using Node.js for backend with Express, NestJS and Fastify, just for fun and learning purposes
- I created chatbots and crawlers using Puppeteer and Cheerio.
- ES6+, clean code, ESLint, Prettier, EditorConfig always.

ELIXIR

- One of my side languages for side projects
- Using Phoenix to create APIs and LiveView for fullstack projects.
- Handling with databases relational and non relation using Ecto.
- Using the tools for code analysis: credo and dialyxir.
- I intend to work with Elixir, because of the tolerance fault and the high scalable systems.

НТМІ

• I've been using HTML following best practices with semantics and the ally guide for creating semantic and accessible web apps.

CSS

• I've been using Vanilla CSS or SASS as a pre-processor, working with BEM methodology and following best practices for a good and beautiful CSS. Most of the cases using flexbox or grid.

Rust

- Side language to create side projects
- Focusing on typesafe and performatic scripts

R

- Using with Bioconductor packages as limma and GEOQuery.
- · Data wrangling and visualization using ggplot2, tidyr, dplyr
- Integrations with relational and non-relational databases.
- · Creation of dashboard using Shiny apps.

LINUX

· Open source enthusiast since 2004. I all just wanted was make some free phone calls and this lead me to linux and other stuff like shell scripting.

DEVOPS

- Worked with virtualization using Docker.
- · Continuous integration and continuous deploy with Jenkins, CircleCI, SonarQube, Fortify, Github Actions, Cloudflare, Netlify and Vercel.
- Worked using GCP. Working with AWS right now(EC2, S3, Cloudfront, LightSail, Amplify)

Languages

Portuguese

Native speaker

ENGLISH

• C1 Level